Link, Eugene P.; Papers apap025
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Materials Relating to the Religious Freedom Committee (RFC), 1954-1964; 8; 0.5 cubic ft.
  Organized by Harry F. Ward in 1952 at the suggestion of Methodist pastor, Lee Ball (who was largely reacting to the McCarthyism of the times), the RFC had a national membership of lay people and clergy pledged to work to maintain free exercise of religion as granted by the Bill of Rights. The national executive committee of the RFC consisted of thirty-five and an administrative committee of seventeen consisted of Catholic, Protestant, and Jewish members who were both black and white. The steering committee which was the true energizing force of the RFC included Ward, Ball, Richard Morford (long-time director of the National Council of American-Soviet Friendship), and William Howard Melish, an Episcopal priest. The lawyer of the group was Royal France, whose wife, Ruth, was an active admirer of Ward.
  The Link Papers contain the Administrative Committee Minutes of the RFC from 1960-64; the original supporters/sponsors list of the RFC, 1950s-early 1960s; various pamphlets of the organization; and the Religious Freedom News, the official organ of the RFC. The RFC was disbanded in 1965 and many of its ongoing concerns were taken up by the Methodist Federation of Social Action.
  - Administrative Committee Minutes of the RFC, 02/08/1960-11/23/1964; 3 folders (Box 7 (8-Materials Relating to the Religious Freedom Commit), Folder 4-6)
  - Original Supporters/Sponsors List of the RFC, 1950s-early 1960s (Box 7 (8-Materials Relating to the Religious Freedom Commit), Folder 7)
  - RFC Membership Mailing Labels, ca. 1960; photocopies (Box 7 (8-Materials Relating to the Religious Freedom Commit), Folder 8)
  - RFC Pamphlets, 1960-1964 (Box 7 (8-Materials Relating to the Religious Freedom Commit), Folder 9)
  - Religious Freedom News (organ of the RFC) [incl. transcript of the Uphaus v. Wyman case], 1954-1964 (Box 7 (8-Materials Relating to the Religious Freedom Commit), Folder 10)
- Oversize and Miscellaneous Materials, 1944; 1979; 9; 0.4 cubic ft.
  This series contains two items that, because of size and subject, do not fit easily into any of the other series. The two items are a religious instructional book given to the Link family in 1944 by Clarence V. Hourell and the 1979 plaque awarded to Link by the International Who's Who of Education.
  - "Let's Go To Church", Book Given to Links By Clarence V. Hourell, 1944 (Box 7 (9-Oversize and Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 11)
  - International Who's Who in Education, Plaque Awarded to Link, 1979 (Box 7 (9-Oversize and Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 12)
  - Bethune Slides, Undated (Box 7 (9-Oversize and Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 14)